<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog posts on abhi sundu gamedev blog</title>
    <link>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog posts on abhi sundu gamedev blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022-2024, Abhi Sundu, all rights reserved </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 11:52:50 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Results one year after my first commercial game</title>
      <link>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/yearofpsu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/yearofpsu/</guid>
      <description>I released Putrid Shot Ultra on Steam roughly one year ago, on November 7, 2022.
Sales The game sold around 840 units on Steam in the ~1 year since its release. The game also has around 1800 outstanding wishlists. In the first month, the game sold around 300 units, so it&amp;rsquo;s definitely surpassed my expectations one year later. The sales graph for the game shows spikes during every Steam sale/discount after the release:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I get people to play my free games</title>
      <link>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/marketing-free-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 12:14:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/marketing-free-games/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of info out there on how to market paid games, but most of these are steam-focused. Marketing on Steam is a slightly different beast than marketing a random itch game you posted for free.
Additionally, it&amp;rsquo;s tough to get non-gamedev, &amp;ldquo;unsympathetic&amp;rdquo; feedback. This is my process for getting eyes on my free games.
Make a game that&amp;rsquo;s playable in a web browser Post the browser version of your game to itch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defense of Blood Vials: &#39;Eat Your Vegetables&#39; game design</title>
      <link>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/bloodvials-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/bloodvials-defense/</guid>
      <description>People really hate farming blood vials
This is a pretty common criticism of Bloodborne, especially since the healing system is so different from Dark Souls&amp;rsquo;s renowned estus flask system. &amp;ldquo;Why would the developers ever force the player to &amp;ldquo;farm&amp;rdquo; a healing item? This just makes me madder. I just want to keep fighting the boss!&amp;rdquo;
Take a break, kid &amp;ldquo;Go take a break. You&amp;rsquo;ve died to this guy like 30 times already, go do something else for a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamedev, Monetization, and Lottery Tickets</title>
      <link>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/gamedevlottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 10:27:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/gamedevlottery/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I released my first commercial game, the temptation to monetize my most fun hobby has been violently oscillating. I wrote a little bit about this in my post-mortem for my game Six Cards Under, a previously-paid-but-free-now game I released back in October.
Sometimes I feel like commercial gamedev is my own personal lottery ticket.
If I try enough, I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually win, right? My first commercial game has sold about 600 units so far on Steam since its release in November, for a total of around 1500 dollars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I spent 938 hours making games over the last 3.5 years</title>
      <link>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/timetracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/timetracking/</guid>
      <description>Over the past three and a half years, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent 938 hours making different games. The games ranged from short projects taking only 20-30 hours to much longer projects taking upwards of 200 hours with many unfinished projects scattered in between.
While some went unfinished, most of the projects ended up shipping in one way or another. In tracking my gamedev time, I learned how long it takes me to &amp;ldquo;make a thing&amp;rdquo;, what types of projects cause me to burn out, and how time tracking affects the way I work in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results from my first Steam Game: PUTRID SHOT ULTRA Postmortem</title>
      <link>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/psupostmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 10:13:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhisundu.github.io/posts/psupostmortem/</guid>
      <description>I released my first commercial steam game, PUTRID SHOT ULTRA, on November 7 2022. I spent 6 months working on this game in my free time for a total of about ~200 hours of work. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the results of my game, my process, and some analysis on why my game performed the way it did.
Summary of Results My game sold 285 copies in 3 weeks following its release.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
